FIELD OPERATIONS MANAGER

Professional Summary

Welder with several years of fabrication and pipe fitting experience. Skilled in determining project requirements, including scope and assembly sequences. Well-Versed in reading and interpreting blueprints, technical manuals, system specifications and associated references to maintain proper quality control and safety standards. \hat{A} \hat{A} \hat{a}

Highlights

- Journeyman Welder
- Blueprint reading
- Plumber
- Forklift operator
- Shielded metal arc welding
- Gas metal arc welding
- Gas Tungsten arc welding
- Silver brazing
- Soft solder brazing
- Skilled fabricatorÂ

ÂÂâ€∢

Experience

Microsoft Corporation October 2015 to Current Field Operations Manager

Chicago, IL

I was hired for this position by my previous operational manager at Fraser's services, Dale Lacey when Fraser's closed its doors in San Diego. I am retired Navy so I have the ability to travel, work part time when, where or for how ever long needed for Mare Island Dry Dock. I'v long been the person Dale could count on to get the job done. I am currently managing a project on a 100 Ton Floating Navy Crain nearing completion on the Navy Base in San Diego. This project required the Dry Docking of the vessel for a complete outer shell preservation and numerous other repairs on piping, pumps, valves, heavy structural and hull plating.

Supervisor: Dale Lacey (619) 210-4084.

â€≀

Col Care July 2014 to February 2015 Sales Associate

Vineland, NJ

I was assigned to the hardware department, where the years of experience in repair, craftsmanship and problem solving ability, enabled me to easily assist customer's with projects they are working on. Answering any questions and offering advice with hardware, lumber or tools that may be required to complete the their project needs.

Supervisor: Jose Casillas (619) 589-2999.

Arctic Slope Regional Corporation January 2014 to March 2014 Welding Foreman Nuiqsut, AK

I was responsible for the completion of all structural repairs. Conducted site checks to evaluate job specifications to determine what specific skill set would be required. I reviewed drawings order material, monitored work in progress to ensure that all welding procedures, fit up, weld joint design, fabrication and quality requirements were maintained. I assisted and provided on site training as required.

Supervisor: Alex Fernandez (619) 474-5491.

Kimpton Hotels June 2007 to November 2013 Project Manager GA , State

I was responsible for the execution of waterfront availabilities. I reviewed negotiated Job specifications for technical accuracy and compliance to standards so work could be accomplished within a planned scheduled availability. I monitored work in progress to ensured that all quality standards were maintained and implemented corrective actions as needed to meet both acceptance standers and time lines. I coordinated shop manpower levels and sub-contractors to ensure jobs were maned at proper levels and resolved any problems that accrued during the production phase. I scheduled and oversaw all quality assurance checkpoints required by the Government for Fraser's services and subcontractors. I conducted weekly production meetings with government project managers, commanding officers, ships force personal and subcontractors to ensure an efficient flow of information, progression of jobs and to address any material, or technical problems.

Supervisor: Dale Lacey (619) 210-4084.

Mcdonald's April 2005 to June 2007 Forman / Lead Welder

El Paso, TX

I was responsible for hiring and the training of all the companies certified welders, Pipe Fitters and Brazers. Additionally I assigned all welding and fabrication jobs based on the qualifications and skill level required. I held company welding certifications to weld on Aluminum, Copper Nickel, stainless Steel, Mild Steel and High yield Steel using the following process. Shielded metal arc welding (SMAW) gas tungsten arc welding (GTAW)

gas metal arc welding (GMAW) and silver braze. I scheduled all required quality assurance in-process and end point testing. Visual (VT) Magnetic Particle (MT), Dye Penetrate (PT), Ultrasonic (UT) and hydrostatic testing.Â

Supervisor: Dale Lacey (619) 210-4084.

Pacific Production Plumbing Plumber October 2004 to April 2005 Finish Plumber

City, STATE Installed sinks, hot tubs, bath tubs, hot water heaters, back flow valves, faucets, toilets, Â supply and drain lines as required.

Supervisor: Joe C (619) 654-0692.

United States Navy January 2000 to July 2004 Chief Petty Officer City, STATE

Shop Master for the weld shop and the sheet metal shop at 32nd street Naval Station. I was responsible for the administrative and technical supervision of 15 to 20 personal. Planned work to be accomplished, set priorities, prepared work schedules and made calculated decisions on work problems. I conducted shipboard inspections to verify ship's material condition to determine actual scope of work required and quality of work completed. Attended weekly production meetings with Commanding Officers, Contractors, and Senior Leadership providing advice / guidance and updating the progress of incoming and out going work.

United States Navy February 1983 to January 2004 Hull Maintenance Technician

City, STATE Â Engineering department, considered the maintenance personal of the ship. Tasked with the repair and maintenance of ship's equipment to include but not limited to all welding and silver braze of ship board ferrous and non-ferrous piping systems. Steam, fuel oil, fresh water, salt water, sewage and Freon. Maintained all of the sanitary spaces insuring proper operation of valves, pumps, tanks, and operational alarms. Repaired adjusted and replaced doors, joiner and water tight. Considered the fire fighting experts, providing training and preformed the maintenance and testing of all the fire fighting equipment on board the ship.

Education

C-1 Weld School 1987 City, State, United States This was a two phase school that started out with twenty personal. The first Phase was the general maintenance welder 4954. The second phase was 4955 high pressure pipe welder only the top 10 students were allowed to proceed to the next phase.

1982 High School Diploma City, State, United States

Certifications

Navy Welding NEC 4955 High pressure pipe welder, NAVSEA Collecting Holding and Transfer (sewage) system Certification inspector, Finish Plumber, Forklift Operator, Navy and commercial Competent person, training for gas free and confined space entry Certifications.

I am active with and a life time member of the Veterans Of Foreign Wars.

Skills

WelderÂ

Metal fabricator.

Quality Assurance Inspector.

Forklift Operator.

Gas Free Competent person, for confined space entry.

â€∢